<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Ty Scales</title>
    <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Ty Scales</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 13:40:50 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://tscales.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>John of Ravenna</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume3/john-of-ravenna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 13:40:50 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume3/john-of-ravenna/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 16 in a series on Daniel Farlati&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../../&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;John of Ravenna was the first bishop of Spalato, modern day Split, south of the destroyed city of Salona. According to Thomas the Archdeacon, the city was made up of Salonitans returning to the mainland from the islands they had fled from during the seige of Salona. He writes in &lt;em&gt;historiae Salonitanae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Now among the Salonitans, who had gone to the nearest islands, there was a certain man named Severus, whose house was near the columns of the Palace above the sea. Because he had greater authority than the rest, he was called the great Severus. He began to exhort his fellow citizens to return to their homeland. But because it was not safe to place ancient fortresses among the ruins of the city, he advised them to retreat to the building of Diocletian, where, dwelling more securely, they could inhabit some high part of their territory without great fear, until, if things went well, it would be possible to rebuild Salona.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programming Without Structs</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/programming-without-structs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2025 18:25:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/programming-without-structs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Krzysztof Kowalczyk writes in his &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.kowalczyk.info/article/d-2025-06-26/go-is-8020-language.html&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; on the go programming language:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Go has shown that you can have a popular language without enums. I don’t think you could have a popular language without structs. There’s a line below which the language is just not useful enough.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What would it look like if we didn&amp;rsquo;t have structs? The core idea of struct is a covenient way to store and access data. We woud need to substitute our struct for another primitive type that can hold data. A map provides similar lookup capabilities by using a key, with less gaurantees that a field might even be present.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Table of Contents</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/table-of-contents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 15:37:58 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/table-of-contents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A translation of the table of contents for volume II of Daniel Farlati&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../../&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;, along with some notes. This covers the bishops of Salona from the 4th to the 7th century, The destruction of Salona, a biography of Diocletian, and some hagiographies associated with him.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;marinus-i-martinus-i-maximus-iii-theodorus-ii-petrus-ii-leo-i-joannes-iv-bishops-of-salona&#34;&gt;Marinus I. Martinus I. Maximus III. Theodorus II. Petrus II. Leo I. Joannes IV. Bishops of Salona&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Several catalogues place these 7 bishops in the seventh century, and in different orders.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The roman Catalogue puts them in the 4th century&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Not much is remembered of these bishops and the 100 years their rules spanned.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-on-marinus-and-martin-bishops-of-salona&#34;&gt;1. On Marinus and Martin, Bishops of Salona&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Marinus I. 23rd Bishop of Salona.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Martinus I. 24th Bishop of Salona&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-marinus-and-martin&#34;&gt;notes on Marinus and Martin&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;316 - 340 AD, Farlati splits the reigns evenly at 12 years a piece for seemingly no logical reason.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;farlati must explain why Marinus was not at the council of Nicea in 325&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Constantine redefines the boundaries of Illyria&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Arius is said to have been banished among the Illyrians during the council&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-maximus-iii-25th-bishop-of-salona-7&#34;&gt;2. Maximus III. 25th Bishop of Salona. 7.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Maximus&amp;rsquo; orthodox and sincere faith in God.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What Maximus accomplished in his episcopate, or what happened in his time worthy of commemoration.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-maximus-iii&#34;&gt;Notes on Maximus III&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Called by other Catalogs Marinus II.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flavius Rufinus Sarmentius was governor of dalmatia during this time.&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;VIRTUTE, ET FELICITATE OMNES RETRO PRINCIPES SUPER GRESSO D. N. H. JUL. CONSTANTI VICTORI, AC TRIUPHATORI SEMPER AUG. FL. JUL. RUFINUS SARMENTITIUS V.C PRAESES PROV. DALMATIAE D. N. M. EIUS.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mentioned by name in the epistles the semiarians sent during the Council of Serdica. Socrates Scholasticus mentions these letters being drafted.&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Council_of_Serdica&#34;&gt;Council of Serdica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hilary of Poitiers seems to have preserved it in &lt;em&gt;Collectanea Antiariana Parisina&lt;/em&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;[Collectanea Antiariana Parisina]https://scaife.perseus.org/reader/urn:cts:latinLit:stoa0149b.stoa002.opp-lat1:1.4.1.pr.1/&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Gregorio Alexandriae episcopo, Nicomediae episcopo. Carthaginis episcopo. Campaniae episcopo, Neapolis Campaniae episcopo. Ariminensi clero. Campaniae episcopo. Salonae Dalmatiae episcopo, Amfioni, Donato, Desiderio, Fortunato, Euthieio, Maximo, Sinferonti et omnibus per orbem terrarum consacerdotibus nostris presbiteris et diaconibus et omnibus. qui sub caelo sunt in ecclesia&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;but the catholic encyclopedia says that the maximus referred to is Maximin of Trier&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Anathasius writes in his Apology that the bishops from Dalmatia supported him.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-theodore-ii-26th-bishop-of-salona-17&#34;&gt;3. Theodore II 26th bishop of Salona. 17.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Christian and Ecclesiastical Affairs under Theodore, Bishop of Salona, ​​from the year 350 of Christ to the year 360&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the Christian affairs from 360 to 365 AD, and the death of Theodore, Bishop of Salonica.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-thedore-ii&#34;&gt;Notes on Thedore II&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;nothing remembered of this bishop.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;in &lt;em&gt;Fragmenta Ex Libro Provinciae Aquitaniae&lt;/em&gt;, Hilary of Potiers preserves a letter the bishops of Italy sent to the bishops of Illyricum applauding them on their rejection of Arianism. Farlati thinks it was sent while Theodore was Bishop.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hilarion is said to have traveled to the coastal Dalmatian town of Epidaurus. A legend is attributed to him that he miraculously calmed the sea after an earthquake.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-peter-ii-leo-i-john-iv-27&#34;&gt;4. Peter II, Leo I, John IV. 27.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Peter II, 27th bishop of Salona. On the Illyrian Council&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What worthy of mention happened in Dalmatia, Illyricum, and other regions to Peter, Bishop of Salonica, from the 365 to 380 AD&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Leo, 28th bishop of Salona from 380 to 395 AD&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;John IV, 29th bishop of Salona from 395 to 405 AD&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the Monastic Institute Imported and Propagated into Dalmatia&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the multiple arrival and incursion of barbarians into Illyricum and Dalmatia&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-peter-ii-leo-i-and-john-iv&#34;&gt;Notes on Peter II, Leo I, and John IV&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Illyrian Synod, date and location disputed, was held somewhere around 365-375 AD. The Epistle from this synod is republished here from Book IV of theodoret&amp;rsquo;s church history.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Theodoret also preserves a letter in Book II, which addresses the bishops of Illyria after the council of Rome in 382 AD&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;councils of constantinople, Aquileia, and Rome in the 380s. No mention of Leo, althought Aquileia mentions Anemius Bishop of Sirmium present. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tertullian.org/fathers/ambrose_letters_01_letters01_10.htm#132&#34;&gt;Ambrose&amp;rsquo;s letters&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.documentacatholicaomnia.eu/02m/0520-0520,_Rusticus_Helpidius,_In_Historiam_Testamenti_Veteris_Et_Novi_Carmina,_MLT.pdf&#34;&gt;Felix Jardentius&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Synod of Milan: Felix is also present here. Felix is attributed by many writers to be the earliest known bishop of Zadar. a coastal city in the north of Croatia. Count Louis Voinovitch in &lt;a href=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/a/a9/Dalmatia_and_the_Jugoslav_movement_%28IA_dalmatiajugoslav00vojn%29.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dalmatia and The Jugoslav Movement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;ldquo;the Latin title of the Archbishop of Zara is to this day Archiepiscopus Jadertinus&amp;rdquo;. Jovinian is declared a heretic and exiled to &amp;ldquo;the isle of Bua&amp;rdquo; in the Adriatic sea.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Peter, Leo, and John IV not mentioned at any of the 4th century synods. Some Illyrians mentioned present as described in the notes above.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Monastic tradition of the Dalmatian Islands:&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jerome in Epistle 60: mentions the islands of Dalmatia as an area of monastic activity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.teof.uni-lj.si/uploads/File/BV/BV2021/02/Ciglenecki.pdf&#34;&gt;Ciglenečki and Bobovnik&lt;/a&gt;:&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;epistle 105. Jerome says of a letter he never received from Augustine, that even the an island in the Adriatic had possession of a copy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;epistle 118, to a certain Julian. Whom Jerome says built Monasteries on the islands of Dalmatia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;against rufinus&lt;/em&gt;, Jerome says the Dalmatian Islands were aware of the books Rufinus had written against Jerome&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bonosus: friend of Jerome who eventually moved to an unknown Island.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;epistle 68: A monastic community is present on the island of Cissa&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hesychius-iii-30th-bishop-of-salona-64&#34;&gt;Hesychius III. 30th bishop of Salona. 64.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-hesychius-is-restored-to-the-church-of-salonica-from-which-he-had-been-stolen-66&#34;&gt;1. Hesychius is restored to the Church of Salonica, from which he had been stolen. 66.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the Commentary on the Bishopric of Toledo by Hesychius&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hesychius is recaptured from Toledo and returned to the Church of Salonica.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-the-acts-of-hescyhius-70&#34;&gt;2. The Acts of Hescyhius. 70.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Life of Hesychius before the Pontificate&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hesychius labors for the restoration of John Chrysostom. He admonishes Ruffinus about the corruptions introduced into the Clementine books by heretics; he restores the afflicted Dalmatians.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pontifical acts of Hesychius from 410 to 420 AD.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the remaining Acts of Hesychius from the year 420 to 438&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-hesychius-iii&#34;&gt;Notes On Hesychius III.&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mentioned by Augustine, wrote him a letter and mentions him in &lt;em&gt;City of God&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;John Chrysostom writes in him a letter from exile (epistle 183)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the Spanish Chronicles, which Farlati had already refuted for earlier bishops, are refuted again here for claiming Hesychius III as a bishop of Toledo.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;the letter from Chrysostom (epistle 183)&#xA;&lt;code&gt;Esti magno itineris intervallo a reverentia tua disjungimur, et ad extremos usque orbis terrarum fines relegati sumus; tamen levi charitatis penna utentes, quae faciles reddit huiusmodi peregrinationes, et propinqui fumus tibi, et tecum versamur, ac debitam per litteras salutationem persolvimus; teque hortamur, ut ad juvandas orientis ecclesias conveniens studium adhibeas. Scis enim, quanta fit parata merces ei, qui divexatis ecclesiis manum porrexerit, et tantam procellam in tranquillitatem converterit, ac bellum adeo grave restinxerit. Atque ad haec vos hortamur, non quasi admonitione nostra indigtatis; siquidem antequam hostras litteras accepissetis, quae vestri muneris erant, ipsi praestitistis; sed quia nondum sublata sunt mala, sed adhuc vigent, et urgent; oramus vos, ut ne animo concidatis, neque malis cedatis, sed quamdiu manent ulcera, quibus cclesiae corpus affligitur, vestra medicamenta adhibeatis. Quanto enim pluribus cum laboribus res geruntur, tanto vobis amplior etimam merces constituetur.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;pg 73. quoting from the life of saint clement, a letter sent to Rufinus urging him to purge the errors introduced by of the clementine recognitions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hesychius writes a letter to Pope Zosimus, Sozimus responds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-the-works-of-hesychius-83&#34;&gt;3. The works of Hesychius. 83&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lives of Clement, Domnius, Anastasius,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Whether the Commentaries on Leviticus are to be attributed to Hesychius&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Correspondence between Hesychius and Augustine&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-the-works-of-hesychius&#34;&gt;Notes on the Works of Hesychius&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Life of St. Clement. Farlati only has fragments of the work. Simon Bingnius supposedly had 2 copies and sent 1 to the archbishop of split P.D Bernard.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Life of Domnius and Anastasius. Bingnius is also the claimant that they were written by hesychius. The works are covered in volume 1.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 letters known to be written: 1 to Pope zosima, 2 to Augustine. a 4th letter, according to the &lt;em&gt;vita&lt;/em&gt; was written to Rufinus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Leviticus commentaries: evidence points to the Hesychius of Jerusalem.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;john-v-and-peter-iii-91&#34;&gt;John V and Peter III. 91.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-john-v-31st-bishop-of-salona&#34;&gt;1. John V. 31st Bishop of Salona&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;John attended the first National Roman Council held against Nestorius, as well as the second, but not the Ecumenical Council of Ephesus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;John kept the Dalmatian Church untouched by the Nestorian and Pelagian heresies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Huns, having entered Pannonia, destroyed Sirmium, the principal city of Western Illyricum. With the destruction of the city and the church of Sirmium, the metropolitan jurisdiction of the Bishop of Salonica increased.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the remaining acts of John, Metropolitan of Salona, ​​from the year 442 to 450.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-peter-iii-32nd-bishop-of-salona-100&#34;&gt;2. Peter III. 32nd Bishop of Salona. 100.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Peter, receiving and approving Pope Leo&amp;rsquo;s Epistle to Flavian, along with the Bishops of Dalmatia, expressed his opinion on Eutyches, which was confirmed at the Council of Chalcedon.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;whether any part of Attila&amp;rsquo;s calamity spread to Dalmatia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What worthy of mention happened under Peter, Bishop of Salonica, in Dalmatia and Illyricum, in the Church and in both empires, up to the year 468.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Marcellinus obtains the kingdom in Dalmatia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the affairs of the Goths, and of both Empires, until the death of Peter III, Bishop of Salona.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-john-v-and-peter-iii&#34;&gt;Notes on John V and Peter III&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;nothing is remembered besides their names&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The synod of Rome relating to Nestorius, Farlati thinks John was there just by relation of being close to Rome.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;During pontificate of Pope Celestine. The Bacilica of Saint Sabina was built. An inscription in the church reads that a certain Peter, from an unknown city in Illyria, resided over the church. _Culmen Apostolicum cum Coelestinus haberet Primus, et in toto fulgeret Episcopus orbe, Haec, quae miraris, fundavit presbyter urbis Illyrica de gente Petrus, vir nomine tanto Dignus, ex ab ortu Christi nutritus in aula, Pauperibus locuples, sibi pauper; qui bona vitae Praesentis fugiens meruit sperare futuram.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;glycerius-ex-emperor-33rd-bishop-of-salona-114&#34;&gt;Glycerius, Ex-emperor, 33rd bishop of Salona. 114.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-the-life-of-glycerius-before-his-pontificate-115&#34;&gt;1. The life of Glycerius before his pontificate. 115.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Family, country, achievements, and deaths of magistrates before the Empire.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Glycerius takes control of the affairs of the West, and his achievements during his reign.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-on-the-salonitan-pontificate-of-glycerius-117&#34;&gt;2. On the Salonitan Pontificate of Glycerius. 117.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Glycerius becomes Bishop of Salona&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Acts of Glycerius, Bishop of Salona, ​​and memorable events under his Pontificate&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the life and affairs of Glycerius, the Emperor Bishop of Salona. By Ivan Tomko Mrnavić, Bishop of Bosnia. From a book published in Rome in 1631, which is inscribed: The Royal Fertility of Illyrian Sanctity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-concerning-the-pontifical-gap-of-salona-123&#34;&gt;3. Concerning the Pontifical Gap of Salona. 123&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Odoacer&amp;rsquo;s family, military affairs, Italian expedition, Kingdom in Italy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Odoacer, having killed the Tyrant Odiva, avenges the murder of Nepos and gains possession of Dalmatia. Hence arose the causes of the Papal Interregnum of Salona.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On ecclesiastical matters, the see of Salona being vacant.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Theodoric, King of the Ostrogoths, killed Odoacer, and having gained possession of Italy and Dalmatia, brought an end to the Papal interregnum.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-glycerius&#34;&gt;Notes on Glycerius&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jordanes writing in the 6th century &lt;em&gt;Romana&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Nepos, having obtained the legitimate kingdom, expelled Glycerius, who had imposed the kingdom on himself in a tyrannical manner, from the Empire, and made him Bishop of Salona in Dalmatia&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Evagrius Scholasticus in the 6th century &lt;em&gt;Ecclesiastical History&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;ldquo;After whom Glycerius became Emperor. After he was expelled, Nepos obtained the empire of the Romans for five years: and he ordained Glycerius Bishop of Salona in Dalmatia.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paul the Deacon in the 7th century &lt;em&gt;Historia Romana&lt;/em&gt;: &amp;ldquo;Then, in the following year, Nepos unexpectedly arrived with an army, stripped Glycerius of royal power, and ordained him Bishop of Salona, a city in Dalmatia&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;No early writers leave details about his early life. Farlati cites the controversial Ivan Tomko Mrnavić who having read the works of Marcus Maruli claimed that Glycerius was born from a noble family in Salona. He also states to have seen an ancient manuscript from a certain Franciscus Turrigia which suggested Glycerius was not deposed but left voluntarily. &lt;em&gt;Glycerius vero factus fuit Augustus a Gundibaldo Patrio, voluntate totius exercitus, sed postea nolens mundo militare reliquit imperium, et fult factus Episcopus in Salona Dalmatiae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Few references to his short Reign as emperor. Ennodius of Pavia writing in the early 6th century makes a brief favorable mention of him in his life of Epiphanius of Pavia,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;section 3 deals reprints the life of glycerius as written by Ivan Tomko, he claims information from 3 sources: Vincentius de Franciscis, Marcus Marulus (that Glycerius was born a first class citizen in Salona) and Franciscus Turrigia (That Glycerius voluntarily abdicated as opposed to being deposed). Tomko paints a Glycerius in a postiive light saying that he received Julius Nepos in Salona when he fled there, allowing him to stay in the Diocletian Palace. Others have said that When Nepos attempted to raise an Army to retake Rome ~480, Glycerius was involved in the plot to murder him. Marcellinus says it was own men, Viatoris and Ovidae. Anonymus Valesianus also records the death as happening in Salona&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;honorius-ii-34th-bishop-of-salona-133&#34;&gt;Honorius II. 34th Bishop of Salona. 133.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-letter-of-pope-gelasius-to-honorius-bishop-of-salonica&#34;&gt;1. Letter of Pope Gelasius to Honorius, Bishop of Salonica&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First Letter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Second Letter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-acts-of-honorius-bishop-of-salona-136&#34;&gt;2. Acts of Honorius, Bishop of Salona. 136.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honorius keeps the Church of Salonica and the province of Dalmatia untouched by the Eutychian heresy and all schismatic corruption.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Theodoric subdues Pannonia&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honorius founded the church and the bishopric of Barcelona in Pannonia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-on-the-gothic-and-slavonic-kingdom-in-upper-dalmatia-141&#34;&gt;3. On the Gothic and Slavonic kingdom in Upper Dalmatia. 141.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Author, Interpreters, copies of the Slavonic Codex&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the inscription, argument, and authority of the Diocletianic history&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ostroyllus invades Dalmatia, kills the Heruli, and establishes a new kingdom in the province of Praevali.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-honorius-ii&#34;&gt;Notes on Honorius II.&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Roman Catalog reports that the Salonan Pontificate sat vacant for 13 years after Glycerius. Honorius became bishop in 493&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pope Galesius wrote a letter to Honorius in 493 because he had heard the pelagian heresy had begun to spread in Dalmatia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Church of Barcelona. A city otherwise unknown somewhere in Pannonia. Farlati cites Andreas of Zadar who provided the source for this fact at the second council of Salona in the 6th century.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The slavonic Codex mentioned here is the Chronicle of the priest of Dioclea or Duklja. The chronicle details the history of the slavic kingdom and was composed in the 12th century. Marko Marulić, translated the work in latin in the 16th century from a transcription made by Dmine Papalić. Tibor Živković suggests the author of the original codex was Rudger, Archbishop of Bar.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ostroyllus, legendary king who conquered Dalmatia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-januarius-i-hesychius-iv-and-stephen-i-bishops-of-salona-149&#34;&gt;On Januarius I, Hesychius IV, and Stephen I, Bishops of Salona. 149.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-januarius-i-35th-bishop-of-salona-149&#34;&gt;1. Januarius I. 35th Bishop of Salona. 149.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the Affairs of the Church and the Empire from the year 505 to 510.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Letter of King Theodoric to Januarius, Bishop of Salona, and two similar letters of the same to the Prefects of Dalmatia&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The empire of King Theodoric of Italy and Dalmatia is very widely extended; the state of the Illyrian and Dalmatian Churches. The death of Januarius, Bishop of Salonica.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-hesychius-iv-36th-bishop-of-salona-154&#34;&gt;2. Hesychius IV. 36th Bishop of Salona. 154&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the affairs of the Eastern Church, especially of Illyrian, until the death of Emperor Anastasius&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the magistrates of Dalmatia appointed under Theodoric&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Illyricum, and the Eastern Church with Illyricum, and the Western Church returns to harmony. Theodoric harasses the Catholics. His death, as well as the death of Hesychius, Bishop of Salona.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-stephanus-i-or-savilian-37th-bishop-of-salona-158&#34;&gt;3. Stephanus I, or Savilian, 37th bishop of Salona. 158.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What praiseworthy deeds did Stephen perform, or what memorable events occurred during his pontificate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On Dionysius Exiguus; and his letter to Stephen of Salona.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-januarius-i-hesychius-iv-and-stephen-i&#34;&gt;Notes on Januarius I, Hesychius IV, and Stephen I&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Letter of Theodoric to Januarius: preserved by Cassiodorus. Theodoric addresses a complaint that Januarius has not paid a man for the oil that he acquired from him.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dionysius letter to Stephan. Dionysius Exiguus translated a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Collectiones_canonum_Dionysianae&#34;&gt;collection of canons&lt;/a&gt; from Greek to Latin . In several manuscripts his letter to Stephan is prepended, saying it was at Stephan&amp;rsquo;s request that he prepared the translations. Dionysius&amp;rsquo; contemporary Cassiodorus also affirms that Stephan made the the request.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;honorius-iii-38th-bishop-of-salona-161&#34;&gt;Honorius III. 38th bishop of Salona. 161.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-first-provincial-council-of-salona-161&#34;&gt;1. First Provincial Council of Salona. 161.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From whence it is taken, and its truth is vindicated and illustrated.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Acts of the Provincial Council of Salonica.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Notes on the council.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-second-provincial-council-of-salona-172&#34;&gt;2. Second Provincial Council of Salona. 172.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The time of this Council, the cause, the corruption of the actors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Acts of the Second Council of Salona.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Notes on the acts of the second Council of Salona.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-the-gothic-war-177&#34;&gt;3. The Gothic War. 177.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The first year of the Gothic War, 525 AD. The Romans capture Salona, ​​lose it, and regain it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ostroyllus, killed in battle in the first year of the Gothic War, left the kingdom of Praevalita to Senulatus, who made peace with the Romans.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The second year of the Gothic War, 536 AD. The Romans capture Naples and Rome, the Goths invade Dalmatia and attack Salona.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;An epitome of the seven years of the Gothic War until the death of Honorius, Bishop of Salona.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-a-new-description-of-illyricum-from-justinians-_novellae-constitutiones__-185&#34;&gt;4. A new description of Illyricum from Justinian&amp;rsquo;s _Novellae Constitutiones__. 185.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Justinian restored the entire Western Illyricum, with the exception of Noricum, to the Empire after it had been wrested from the Barbarians.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Text from Justinian&amp;rsquo;s Novel 11: &lt;em&gt;De Privilegiis Archiepiscopi Justinianae primae&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;observations in Novel 11&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-the-acts-of-honorius-iii-bishop-of-salonica-collected-together-and-what-happened-during-his-pontificate-worthy-of-memory-191&#34;&gt;5. The Acts of Honorius III, Bishop of Salonica, collected together, and what happened during his Pontificate worthy of memory. 191.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The first thirteen years of Bishop Honorius&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The remaining four years of the Pontificate of Honorius. Of the Patrimony of St. Peter in Dalmatia. Deacon Sebastian, Curator of the Apostolic Patrimony, and Honorius, Bishop of Salona, ​​were rebuked by Pope Vigilius for the Priestly centers and orders instituted and conferred,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-honorius-iii&#34;&gt;Notes on Honorius III&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The extended manuscript of Thomas The Archdeacon&amp;rsquo;s  &lt;em&gt;Historiae Salonitana&lt;/em&gt; is the primary source used by Farlati to discuss the two Councils held during this time. The first council issued 13 decrees related to mainly to administrative affairs of clergy. The second delt with establishing 3 new bishops in Sarsenterum, Muccurum, and Ludrum.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sebastian, who curated the Patrimony in Dalmatia. Pope Vigilius wrote a letter to him accusing him of Simony. By Association this also indicted Honorius. Farlati says he would have already passed by that time, and that no record exists of an official condemnation against him.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-frontinianus-ii-peter-and-probinus-39th-40th-and-41st-bishops-of-salona-194&#34;&gt;On Frontinianus II, Peter, and Probinus. 39th, 40th, and 41st Bishops of Salona. 194.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-frontinianus-ii-39th-bishop-of-salona-194&#34;&gt;1. Frontinianus II. 39th Bishop of Salona. 194.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From whence arose the controversy concerning the three Chapters. What did Justinian and Vigilius decree about them? What did the Easterners and the Westerners think?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Frontinianus, first with great praise, then with great persistence, won the cause of the three chapters, was summoned to Constantinople and driven into exile.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The later nine years of the Gothic war.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-petrus-iv-40th-bishop-of-salona-207&#34;&gt;2. Petrus IV. 40th Bishop of Salona. 207.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;He agreed with the Catholic Church on the condemnation of three chapters, to which he reconciled the Dalmatian schismatics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;concerning matters of great importance to the Church and the Empire, which occurred while Peter was presiding over the Church of Salonica.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-probinus-41st-bishop-of-salona-209&#34;&gt;3. Probinus. 41st Bishop of Salona. 209.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is a not insignificant suspicion that Probinus was infected with the schismatic contagion.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the principal events of that four-year period which is attributed to Probinus, Bishop of Salona.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-frontinianus-ii-peter-iv-and-probinus&#34;&gt;Notes on Frontinianus II, Peter IV, and Probinus&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Three Chapters Controversy: Emperor Justinian&amp;rsquo;s Anathematization of Theodore of 3 earlier Christian authors. Particularly Theodore of Mopsuestia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Facundus of Hermiane writes in &lt;em&gt;libro contra Mocianum&lt;/em&gt; that the Illyrians and Dalmatians were defenders of the three chapters.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Victor of Tunnuna in his Chronicle says that Frontinius was exiled and Peter was put in his place.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;honorius-iv-and-damianus-42nd-and-43rd-bishops-of-salona-211&#34;&gt;Honorius IV and Damianus. 42nd and 43rd Bishops of Salona. 211.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Under Honorius, Bishop of Salona, ​​the Lombards crossed the Julian Alps and founded a kingdom in Italy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On ecclesiastical matters from 566 to 580.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Of the arrival of the Bulgarians, and the friendship formed with them by the kings of Upper Dalmatia. From the priest of Duklja&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-honorius-iv-and-damianus&#34;&gt;Notes on Honorius IV and Damianus&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nothing is remembered of these two bishops.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Chronicle of the priest of Dukja (Pop Dukljanin) which tells of the arrival of the Bulgarians in Northern Dalmatia. Johannes Lucius thought that the author had confused with the Bulgarians with the 8th century Avars.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;natalis-44th-bishop-of-salona-216&#34;&gt;Natalis 44th bishop of Salona. 216.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-on-the-life-and-character-of-natalis-bishop-of-salona-217&#34;&gt;1. On the life and character of Natalis, Bishop of Salona. 217&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;​​from chapter 5 of the Hist. of Salona. 217.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;notes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-observations-on-the-fifth-chapter-of-historiae-salonitanae-218&#34;&gt;2. Observations on the fifth chapter of Historiae Salonitanae. 218&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Natalis was rightly and deservedly criticized by Honorus&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Natalis could not move Honorus from the rank of Archdeacon without injury.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honorus recounted the life and wicked acts of Natalis and the injuries done to him to Pope Pelagius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-the-letter-of-saint-gregory-the-great-to-settle-the-controversy-between-natalis-and-honorus-223&#34;&gt;3. The letter of Saint Gregory the Great to settle the controversy between Natalis and Honorus. 223.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The first letter of Gregory the Great to Archdeacon Honoratus, and the second to Bishop Natalus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Natalus will raise Honorus to the order of the Presbytery, in order to expel the Archdeaconry&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4th letter of Gregory the Great to Natalus&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Letter 5. Gregory the Great to the bishops of Dalmatia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Letter 6. Gregory the Great to Antonius the Subdeacon&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Natalis promises to comply with the Pontifical mandates.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Letter VII. Gregory the Great to Natalus Bishop of Salona&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4the-remaining-acts-of-natalis-bishop-of-salona-and-the-affairs-of-the-empire-and-especially-of-the-dalmatian-church-of-those-times-235&#34;&gt;4.The remaining acts of Natalis, bishop of Salona; and the affairs of the empire, and especially of the Dalmatian church of those times. 235&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The first six years of Natalis are worthy of praise and memory&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Later years of Natalis&amp;rsquo; pontificate. He removed Florentius, bishop of Epidaurus, from his episcopate after being accused of corruption, without the knowledge and without consulting the provincial bishops. Apostolic delegation to inspect the churches of Dalmatia. Death of Natalis.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-the-honored-archdeacon-elected-bishop-by-the-votes-of-the-clergy-and-the-people-voluntarily-resigned-his-pontificate-out-of-a-desire-for-peace-239&#34;&gt;5. The honored Archdeacon, elected Bishop by the votes of the clergy and the people, voluntarily resigned his pontificate out of a desire for peace. 239.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gregory orders Antoninus, his subdeacon, and his apocrypha, by letter, to convene the clergy and people of Salonica and see to it that a bishop is duly elected and replaced by Natalis.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gregory confirms the opinion which he and Pelagius had expressed according to Honoratus, and sends it to him, attested by papal letters, so that no obstacle may block his access to the Salonican Pontificate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honoratus is elected to the Episcopate of Salonica; Pope Gregory confirms the election.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honoratus resigned the episcopate for the cause of removing the Schism, and for the sake of peace.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-natalis&#34;&gt;Notes on Natalis&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Natalis is portrayed as having been honorable in his early years as bishop, but began to neglect his duties in later years.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honoratus, an archdeacon, began to oppose him for his lavish feasts and misuse of the church treasury. Natalis attempts to depose him. Honoratus writes to Pope Pelagius II, and his successor, Gregory the Great.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gregory the great sends several letters in an attempt to resolve the situation. Natalis is slow to respond and Gregory orders Honoratus restored to his position.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gregory also sent letters concerning the bishop Florentinus, who Natalis deposed unlawfully by not calling for a council to review the matter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Natalis died before any of his controversies were resolved. Honoratus was elected bishop. Another bishop, Malchus, managed to turn public opinion against him. Honoratus resigned in order to avoid a schism.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;maximus-iv-45th-bishop-of-salona-246&#34;&gt;Maximus IV. 45th Bishop of Salona. 246.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-summaries-of-the-acts-in-the-case-of-maximus-the-prevaricator-247&#34;&gt;1. Summaries of the Acts in the Case of Maximus the Prevaricator. 247.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Summary from chapter 6 of &lt;em&gt;Historiae Salonitanae&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Summary from book 4, chapter 2 of John the Deacon&amp;rsquo;s Life of Saint Gregory&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Summary III. from Book VII. of the Epistles of St. Gregory the Great. Exists in the Venetian Labbean collection under this title: “On the cause of the greatest Prevaricator, his satisfaction, and penance”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Appendix from the Pontifical Chronicle of Salona&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-a-previous-commentary-on-the-letters-of-gregorian-pertaining-to-the-cause-of-the-great-bishop-of-salonica-249&#34;&gt;2. A previous commentary on the letters of Gregorian pertaining to the cause of the great Bishop of Salonica. 249.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Maximus&amp;rsquo;s race, character, perverse manners, and recruitment into the Salonitan clergy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Maximus is elected Bishop.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Why Maximus was called a Presumptor, Prevaricator, Simoniac, and Schismatic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-letter-of-pope-st-gregory-or-to-maximus-written-for-the-sake-of-others-252&#34;&gt;3. Letter of Pope St. Gregory or to Maximus, written for the sake of others. 252&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First Epistle to the Provincial Bishops of Dalmatia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Letter of St. Gregory to the Presumptuous Maximus&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Letter of St. Gregory to Marcellus Scholasticus&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Letter of St. Gregory to Constantine Augusta&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Second Letter of St. Gregory to the Presumptuous Maximus&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Third letter of St. Gregory to Maximus&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Letter of St. Gregory to Salona&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Letter of St. Gregory to Zadar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Letter of St. Gregory to Sabinianus, Bishop of Zadar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Letter of St. Gregory to Sabinianus, Deacon of Rome&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Second Letter to Sabinianus, Bishop of Zadar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Third letter to Sabinianus, Bishop of Zadar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Letter of St. Gregory to Marcellinus, Proconsul of Dalmatia&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Maximus, having lost the number of his supporters and the patronage of the leading men, repented and promised to carry out the Pope&amp;rsquo;s orders.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Letter of St. Gregory to Constantius, Bishop of Milan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Letter of St. Gregory to Marinianum, Bishop of Ravenna&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Letter of St. Gregory to Castorius, Notary&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Maximus, by taking an oath, purges himself of simony and of other crimes by infamy, and, having duly performed the prescribed penance, is reconciled to the Church and the Apostolic faith.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Letter of St. Gregory to Maximus. He sent him a pallium.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-acts-of-maximus-bishop-of-salona-and-the-more-notable-events-of-those-times-especially-in-dalmatia&#34;&gt;4. Acts of Maximus, Bishop of Salona, and the more notable events of those times, especially in Dalmatia&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Of the six previous annals of Bishop Maximus, not legitimate, but intrusive.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The ten intermediate years of the pontificate of Maximus, bishop of Salona&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the last ten years of Maximus, Bishop of Salona&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-maximus&#34;&gt;Notes on Maximus&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;John the Deacon writes in his &lt;em&gt;vita Gregorii&lt;/em&gt; that Maximus bribed soliders to ensure his election as bishop.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;He was the subject of several letters by Gregory the Great, either to him or concerning his behavior.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The byzantine emperor Maurice requested Gregory to recognize Maximus&amp;rsquo; position.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gregory requested Maximus to come to Rome to face the accusations made against him. He delayed and rejected this request. Gregory sent a letter to Salona publicly announcing his excommunication.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Maximus eventually fell out of favor and petitioned Gregory for penance. He traveled to Ravenna where he was confirmed to be absolved and readmitted to the church.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;He would return to Salona and remain Bishop for another 20 years.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://la.wikisource.org/wiki/Epistolae_(Gregorius_Magnus)&#34;&gt;Letters of Gregory the Great&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;frontinianus-iii-46th-bishop-of-salona-295&#34;&gt;Frontinianus III. 46th Bishop of Salona. 295.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-on-the-pontificate-of-frontinianus-iii-bishop-of-salona-296&#34;&gt;1. On the Pontificate of Frontinianus III, bishop of Salona. 296.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The affairs of the Church and the Empire from the year 20 to 30 of the seventh century.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Of the remaining eight years of Frontinian, Bishop of Salona, ​​and his death.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-frontinianus-iii&#34;&gt;Notes on Frontinianus III.&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nothing is remembered of Frontinianus. The city of Salona was destroyed shortly after his death.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;theodorus-iii-47th-and-last-bishop-of-salona-300&#34;&gt;Theodorus III. 47th and Last Bishop of Salona. 300.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-on-the-state-of-the-city-and-church-of-salonica-300&#34;&gt;1. On the state of the city and church of Salonica. 300.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the corrupt morals of citizens.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the small number of troops which were then in Salona and in other cities of Dalmatia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-description-of-the-city-cut-down-and-overthrown-from-constantine-vii-porphyrogenitus-and-thomas-the-archdeacon-302&#34;&gt;2. Description of the city cut down and overthrown: from Constantine VII Porphyrogenitus and Thomas the Archdeacon. 302.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From Constantine Porphyrogenitus&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;De Administrando Imperio&lt;/em&gt; Chapter 29.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From Chapter 30 of &lt;em&gt;De Administrando Imperio&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From chapter 3 of Thomas The Archdeacon&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Historiae Salonitanae&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-observations-on-the-exceprts-of-constantine-porphyrogenitus-and-thomas-the-archdeacon-306&#34;&gt;3. Observations on the Exceprts of Constantine Porphyrogenitus and Thomas the Archdeacon. 306.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;At what time was Salona captured and overthrown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What kind of barbarians were the overthrowers of Salona?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salona was attacked and captured, burned and demolished.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-what-followed-after-the-destruction-of-salona-before-the-city-of-split-was-founded-315&#34;&gt;4. What followed after the destruction of Salona before the city of Split was founded. 315.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The flight and dispersion of the Salonitans.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Avars and Slavs ravaged Dalmatia, Upper Moesia, and Istria.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Abbot Martin was sent by John IV to Dalmatia and Istria to redeem captives and transfer the relics of martyrs to the city.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Chrobati and Serbs wage war on the Avars, and after expelling them, they gain control of Mediterranean Dalmatia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Salonitans, having returned from the islands to the mainland, some founded Ragusium with the Epidaurians, others Jadria&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What happened in the Metropolitan Interregnum of Dalmatia, from the overthrow of Salona to the founding of Spalatum, was worthy of memory in the church and empire.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-theodorus-iii&#34;&gt;Notes on Theodorus III.&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nothing is remembered of Theodorus except that he was said to be bishop during the destruction of Salona. It is not known how he died.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thomas the Archdeacon in &lt;em&gt;historiae Salonitanae&lt;/em&gt; chapter 7: the city of Salona had devolved in to a corrupt city.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;destruction of Salona. Documented by Constantine VII Porphyrogenitus and thomas the archdeacon. The avars invaded. Many Salonans fled to the islands, eventually dispersing to other coastal cities, some returning to start the city of Split.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chronological-synopsis-from-316-to-650-ad-326&#34;&gt;Chronological Synopsis from 316 to 650 AD. 326.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-history-of-emperor-diocletian-the-birth-of-salona-338&#34;&gt;The History of Emperor Diocletian. The birth of Salona. 338.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-on-the-race-of-aurelia-valeria-of-salona-or-on-the-family-and-kindred-of-the-emperor-diocletian-the-holy-of-the-saints-and-martyrs-genealogical-difference-338&#34;&gt;1. On the race of Aurelia Valeria of Salona, ​​or on the family and kindred of the Emperor Diocletian, the holy of the saints and martyrs. Genealogical Difference. 338.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the lineage of the Valerian tribe of Salona.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Of the first line of the race of Valeria of Salona, ​​or of the family of Diocletian.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the homeland of Diocletian.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the names of Diocletian.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the wives of Diocletian.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the adopted sons and grandsons of Diocletian.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the second line of the Aurelian family of Valeria of Salona, ​​or on the family of the Holy Caius and Gabinius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the third line of the race of Valeria of Salona; or on the family of St. Claudius and Maximus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the fourth linen of the nation of Valeria of Salona, ​​or on the family of the upright emperor.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-acts-of-the-emperor-diocletian-356&#34;&gt;2. Acts of the Emperor Diocletian. 356.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Of the beginnings of Diocletian, and the era of the martyrs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the affairs of Diocletian from the beginning of his reign to the year 293.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the year 293, Diocletian created Constantius and Galerius Caesars; he divided the Roman Empire into four parts; he celebrated the decennial anniversary in Rome.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the affairs of Diocletian from the year 294 to the year 297. He fought successfully with the Quincentians and the Alemanni in the West, and with the Alexandrians and Persians in the East.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The affairs of Diocletian from the year 297 to 300. Defection of the Dalmatians, Siege of Salona, ​​overthrow of the city of Ariminum.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The affairs of Diocletian from the year 300 to 303.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diocletian decrees a persecution of the entire Church, celebrates the 20th anniversary in Rome, and returns to the field of Nicomedia. From the year 303 to the year 305.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diocletian abdicates the Empire with Maximian. Causes and year of abdication&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diocletian creates new Augustuses and new Caesars, dividing the Roman world into four parts, and assigning provinces to each of them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-of-the-private-life-of-diocletian-after-the-empire-was-laid-down-and-of-the-public-affairs-which-he-lived-and-performed-during-his-life-397&#34;&gt;3. Of the private life of Diocletian after the empire was laid down, and of the public affairs which he lived and performed during his life. 397.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diocletian, having dismissed the insignia of high rank, retained some of the supreme authority and public government.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Constantintius Chlorus dies. His son Severus becomes emperor. Maximian revolts. Severus is succeeded by Licinius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the death of Herculius, Maxentius, and Galerius. Diocletian holds the tenth consulship. He is believed to have favored Maxentius and Maximinus. He refused to attend Licinius&amp;rsquo; wedding, although invited; he was affected with great bitterness and fear by the torn images and the threatening letters of Constantine and Licinius. He vainly complains to Maximinus that his daughter Valeria was treated in an unworthy manner.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diocletian dies at Salona. Time and cause of death. On the beauty of the same and its aptness.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-the-diocletian-persecution-415&#34;&gt;4. The Diocletian Persecution. 415.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the Diocletian persecution in particular. The first period.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the martyrs of Aquileia. Whether the sisters Agape, Ghionia, and Irene of Aquileia are to be distinguished from the other three sisters of the same name of Thessalonica.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The second period of the Diocletian persecution.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The third period of the diocletian persecution.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diocletian, the author of the tenth universal persecution, instigated by Galerius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Of the year, month, and day of the universal persecution.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the cruelty of the tenth persecution.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the Illyrian martyrs under Diocletian, Galerius, and Licinius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the beginning, progress, and end of the Diocletian persecution.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;on-the-licinian-persecution-appendix-457&#34;&gt;On the Licinian persecution. Appendix. 457.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;chronological-synopsis-history-and-diocletian-persecution-465&#34;&gt;Chronological Synopsis. History and Diocletian Persecution. 465.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;saint-serena-empress-and-wife-of-diocletian-augustus-471&#34;&gt;Saint Serena, Empress and Wife of Diocletian Augustus. 471&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-on-saint-serena-augusta-her-marriage-to-the-emperor-religion-sanctity-death-and-cult-472&#34;&gt;1. On Saint Serena Augusta, her marriage to the Emperor, religion, sanctity, death, and cult. 472.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Testimonies from martyrologies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Testimonies from the Hagiologists.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-acts-of-saint-serena-wife-of-diocletian-excerpts-from-other-acts-of-the-saints-474&#34;&gt;2. Acts of Saint Serena wife of Diocletian, excerpts from other acts of the saints. 474.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From the Acts of Saint Susanna with Lippomanus and Surius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From the Acts of Pope Marcellus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-from-the-life-of-artemis-476&#34;&gt;3. From the life of Artemis. 476.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Acts of Saint Serena.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Notes on the Acts of Saint Serena.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-the-origin-and-homeland-of-saint-serena-477&#34;&gt;4. The origin and homeland of Saint Serena. 477.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serena did not originate from Spain.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is more likely that Serena originated from Illyricum than from Spain.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-the-marriage-of-diocletian-and-serena-as-well-as-the-history-of-st-susanna-is-vindicated-by-the-arguments-presented-480&#34;&gt;5. The marriage of Diocletian and Serena, as well as the History of St. Susanna, is vindicated by the arguments presented. 480.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Arguments taken from Lactantius, with which both are attacked.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Baluzian argument is dissolved, and Lactantius is reconciled with the Augustal marriage of St. Serena and with the Acts of St. Susanna.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our interpretation is very much in line with Lactantius&amp;rsquo; way of speaking.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The same explanation is based on the example and authority of Lacttantius&amp;rsquo; interpreters.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our interpretation is confirmed by the example of ancient authors, such as Lactantius and the authority of the aqualia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The interpretation of Lactantius, used by his adversaries, diminishes and weakens the authority of sacred antiquity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It is an insult to prefer the authority of the Lactantian Code to the Martyrologies and Acts of St. Susanna.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Another way to dilute the proposed argument.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some other obstacles are removed that could be placed on Serena&amp;rsquo;s wedding.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-on-the-death-burial-and-relics-of-st-serena-499&#34;&gt;6. On the death, burial, and relics of St. Serena. 499.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-serena&#34;&gt;Notes on Serena&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serena has since been removed from the Roman Martyrology given the lack of sources that mention here.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;only mentioned in passing in the &lt;em&gt;acts of Artemia&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;acts of Pope Marcellus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lactantius States in &lt;em&gt;De mortibus persecutorum&lt;/em&gt; that Diocletian&amp;rsquo;s wife was named Prisca.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;saint-artemia-daughter-of-the-emperor-diocletian-and-serena-augusta-virgin-and-martyr-501&#34;&gt;Saint Artemia, Daughter of the Emperor Diocletian, and Serena Augusta, Virgin and Martyr. 501.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-testimonies-of-ancient-and-modern-writers-on-st-artemia-daughter-of-diocletian-virgin-and-martyr-503&#34;&gt;1. Testimonies of ancient and modern writers on St. Artemia, daughter of Diocletian, virgin and martyr. 503.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From the Martyrologies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;from ancient and modern writers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-acts-of-st-marcellus-pope-and-martyr-in-which-the-conversion-and-martyrdom-of-st-artemia-is-described-506&#34;&gt;2. Acts of St. Marcellus, Pope and martyr, in which the conversion and martyrdom of St. Artemia is described. 506.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cyriacus and Sisinnius were thrown into prison; the Martyrdom of St. Apronian.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The martyrdom of Sisinnius, Saturninus, Papias, and Maurus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Artemia and Jobia, royal virgins, freed from the devil by Saint Cyriacus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The murders of Cyriacus, Crescentianus, Artemias, and others. The constancy of Marcellus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The piety of St. Lucina. The labors and martyrdom of Marcellus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chronological Synopsis.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Appendix: Life of Saint Artemia by Ivan Tomko Mrnavić. Written in Bosnia and printed in Rome in 1631. It exists in that book, to which the title is prefixed by the same author: &lt;em&gt;The Sacredness of Royal Illyrian Sanctity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-the-acts-of-st-marcellus-are-vindicated-by-the-baronial-censors-515&#34;&gt;3. The Acts of St. Marcellus are vindicated by the Baronial Censors. 515.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;That the name of Marcellus should be retained everywhere.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is no reason why Baronius should deny the story of Cyriacus in Persia, or of Jobia, the daughter of King Saporis, who was freed from a demon by him.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;That there are no suppositions, which are mentioned about St. Artemia in the Acts of St. Marcellus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The name of Maximian, from which Baronius wished to be excommunicated, should not be removed from thenceforth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the fourth and last paragraph of the Acts of St. Marcellus, no other person can be understood by the name of Maximian, except Maximianus the Severe.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-on-the-cult-of-st-artemia-virgin-and-martyr--527&#34;&gt;4. On the Cult of St. Artemia, Virgin and Martyr . 527.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Birth or Martyrdom Day; Place of Sepulchre.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Of the relics of St. Artemia, and the translation of his body, and Roman cult.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-artemia&#34;&gt;Notes on Artemia&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Appears in the Bede, Usaurd, and Ado martyrologies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Acts of Marcellus say she was cured of a demon by St. Cyriacus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Like Serena, no mention from Pagan writers or Lactantius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;saint-caius-dalmatian-and-citizen-of-salona-paternal-uncle-of-emperor-diocletian-roman-pontiff-and-martyr-530&#34;&gt;Saint Caius, Dalmatian and citizen of Salona, paternal uncle of Emperor Diocletian, Roman Pontiff and Martyr. 530.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-the-elogia-and-life-of-st-caius-pontiff-of-the-roman-empire-from-various-writers-531&#34;&gt;1. The Elogia and Life of St. Caius, Pontiff of the Roman Empire. From Various Writers. 531.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From the Martyrologies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Acts of S. Caius. From the acts of Saint Sebastian.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From the three Catalogues of the Roman Pontiffs, and from Eusebius of Caesarea.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From the Roman Breviary, Anastasius Bibliothecarius, and &lt;em&gt;Historiae Salonitanae&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From Petrus De Natalibus and Filippo Ferrari.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From Alphonsus Ciacconius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-on-the-name-the-country-and-pontificate-of-st-caius-538&#34;&gt;2. On the Name, the Country, and Pontificate of St. Caius. 538.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the first name of Caius, and its various and multiple ways of writing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the Homeland of St. Caius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the Pontificate of Saint Caius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-on-the-martyrdom-of-st-caius-544&#34;&gt;3. On the Martyrdom of St. Caius. 544.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the Kind of Martyrdom.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the Cause of Death, or Martyrdom.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Of the place of martyrdom, or his departure from this life.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-on-the-discovery-of-the-body-of-st-caius-and-his-relics-548&#34;&gt;4. On the Discovery of the Body of St. Caius and His Relics. 548.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About the first doubtful and uncertain discovery.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Of the second discovery of St. Caius, and that it is certain and confirmed by the testimony of many.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Notes on section 2.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the cities and basilicas which boast of the body of St. Caius being enshrined in them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Where the body of St. Caius is now preserved.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-on-the-cult-of-saint-caius-roman-pontiff-and-martyr-557&#34;&gt;5. On the Cult of Saint Caius, Roman Pontiff and Martyr. 557.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the feast days of St. Caius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Of the remaining three days consecrated to the name of Caius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the cult of St. Caius, Pope and martyr, in the city.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the cult of Pope St Caius in Dalmatia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-caius&#34;&gt;Notes on Caius&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mentioned by Eusebius, but he does not call him a relative of Diocletian, nor do the early martyrologies. The reference seems to come from the acts of Susanna.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;saint-gabinus-presbyter-and-martyr-a-citizen-of-salona-the-parent-of-st-susanna-the-brother-of-st-caius-the-roman-pontiff-and-the-paternal-uncle-of-the-emperor-diocletian-565&#34;&gt;Saint Gabinus, Presbyter and Martyr. A citizen of Salona, ​​the parent of St. Susanna, the brother of St. Caius, the Roman Pontiff, and the paternal uncle of the Emperor Diocletian. 565.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-the-elogia-and-life-of-st-gabinus-presbyter-and-martyr-566&#34;&gt;1. The Elogia and Life of St. Gabinus, Presbyter and Martyr. 566.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From the Martyrologies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The life of Saint Gabinus, compiled into an Epitome from the Acts of St. Susanna. From Petrus De Natalibus, Bishop of Equilinus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-the-martyrdom-of-st-gabinus-568&#34;&gt;2. The Martyrdom of St. Gabinus. 568.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the Nature of Martyrdom.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the Year of the Martyrdom.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the birthday of St. Gabinius, or on the day of his martyrdom.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-on-the-body-and-burial-of-st-gabinus-570&#34;&gt;3. On the Body and Burial of St. Gabinus. 570.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The body of St. Gabinius is still in the temple of St. Susanna in Rome, and other cities falsely boast of his possession.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;St. Gabinus the Martyr, whose body is buried in the Vatican Basilica, is far different from St. Gabinius, priest and martyr, father of St. Susanna.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-gabinus&#34;&gt;Notes on Gabinus&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;primary source is from the &lt;em&gt;Acts of Susanna&lt;/em&gt;. He is called the father of Susanna and the brother of Caius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mentioned by Bede and Ado as the father of Susanna, omitted by Usuard.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;st-susanna-virgin-and-martyr-born-in-dalmatia-daughter-of-gabinus-presbyter-and-martyr-574&#34;&gt;St. Susanna, Virgin and Martyr. Born in Dalmatia. Daughter of Gabinus, Presbyter and Martyr. 574.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-of-susanna-the-virgin-and-martyr-and-her-marriage-decreed-by-maximian-576&#34;&gt;1. Of Susanna the Virgin and Martyr, and her marriage decreed by Maximian. 576.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From the Martyologies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Notes on the martyologies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-acts-of-st-susanna-virgin-and-martyr-from-the-ancient-codices-578&#34;&gt;2. Acts of St. Susanna, Virgin and Martyr, From the ancient Codices. 578.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The family, character, education, and purpose of preserving her virginity of St. Susanna. The conversion of her cousin Claudius to Christ.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Claudius Clarissius, his wife Praepedigna, Alexander and Cuthia are baptized.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Maximus, Count of Private Affairs, the brother of Claudius, was converted to the worship of Christ. Both, along with Praepedigna, Alexander and Cuthia, were killed for Christ, and Gabinius and Susanna were thrown into prison.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Susanna&amp;rsquo;s constancy and martyrdom in rejecting Maximian&amp;rsquo;s marriage. From the Codex Fulda of the Bollandian Museum.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Epitome of the Acts of St. Susanna. From Petrus, Bishop of Equilinus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-of-the-homeland-and-birth-of-susanna-and-the-augustan-marriages-offered-to-her-587&#34;&gt;3. Of the Homeland and Birth of Susanna, and the Augustan Marriages offered to her.. 587.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Where and in what year.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The marriage of Susanna was not decreed to Maximianus Galerius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Saint Susanna was destined to be the wife of Maximianus Herculius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The arguments that can be raised against our opinion are refuted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-on-the-martyrdom-of-st-susanna-594&#34;&gt;4. On the Martyrdom of St. Susanna. 594.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The year of the martyrdom.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The month and day of the martyrdom.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-of-the-sacred-places-susannas-relics-are-ennobled-597&#34;&gt;5. Of the sacred places Susanna&amp;rsquo;s relics are ennobled. 597.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alexander&amp;rsquo;s Cemetery&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Chapel in the House of St. Serena.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The house of St. Gabinus.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Confession of St. Susanna.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Title of St. Susanna.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From the Station to St. Susanna.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The devotion and generosity of the Roman Pontiffs and Cardinals towards the church of St. Susanna, and their care for either decorating or renovating it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the ancient iconography of the temple of St. Susanna.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-susanna&#34;&gt;Notes on Susanna&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Her &lt;em&gt;acts&lt;/em&gt; are the primary source for the other legendary relatives.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diocletian asks Gabinus to have Susanna marry his pagan son Maximus. She refuses and is martyred.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;of-the-holy-martyrs-of-salona-of-the-stock-and-lineage-of-the-emperor-diocletian-claudius-praepedigna-alexander-cuthia-and-maximus-609&#34;&gt;Of the Holy Martyrs of Salona, ​​of the Stock and Lineage of the Emperor Diocletian: Claudius, Praepedigna, Alexander, Cuthia, and Maximus. 609.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-the-elogia-and-life-of-st-claudius-and-his-companions-609&#34;&gt;1. The Elogia and Life of St. Claudius and His Companions. 609.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From the martyrologies and hagiographies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Acts of the Saints of the Five Martyrs, compiled into an Epitome: From Philippo Ferrario in the Catalog of the Saints of Italy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-some-small-questions-or-observations-on-the-acts-of-the-saints-611&#34;&gt;2. Some small questions, or observations on the Acts of the Saints. 611.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Of the country, names, functions, or magistrates.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The year of the conversion and Martyrdom of Claudius and his associates.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the kind and place of martyrdom, on the number and order of martyrs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-claudius-and-his-companions&#34;&gt;Notes on Claudius and his companions&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mentioned in martyrologies, they make a short appearance in the &lt;em&gt;Acts of Susanna&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;index-of-memorable-things-and-words-618&#34;&gt;Index of Memorable Things and Words. 618.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;appendix-marble-of-salona-by-francisco-antonio-zacharia&#34;&gt;Appendix: Marble of Salona by Francisco Antonio Zacharia.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-marble-of-salona&#34;&gt;Notes on Marble of Salona&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;an extensive collection of marble inscriptions found in Salona.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diocletian Family Legends</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/diocletian-family-legends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 10:44:25 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/diocletian-family-legends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 15 in a series on Daniel Farlati&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../../&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Volume II of the Illyricum Sacrum concludes with a series of hagiographies I call the &lt;em&gt;Diocletian Family Legends&lt;/em&gt;. These hagiographies claim that relatives of diocletian were converted to Christianity and martyred for their faith. The names of these saints appear in early martyrologies, but the association with Diocletian is a late addition. Some of these saints which appeared on official martyologies in Farlati&amp;rsquo;s time have since been removed for lack of historical evidence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early Washoe Encounters</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/washoe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 17:35:43 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/washoe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Washoe are the people indegenius to the region of Lake Tahoe, California. The Washoe language is distinct compared to surrounding tribes, leading researchers to believe they have inhabited the area the longest. Estimates put the populate at around 1500 people. The Summer 2025 issue of &lt;em&gt;Tahoe In Depth&lt;/em&gt; reported that just 8 native speakers remain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Encounters with Washoe prior to 1844 likely happened but are speculative at best. Spanish explorers of the San Joquian valley received reports from coastal and plains Indians that they had met people like them who came from the East, possibly traveling from over the Sierra Nevada mountains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Destruction of Salona</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/destruction-of-salona/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 19:00:31 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/destruction-of-salona/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 14 in a series on Daniel Farlati&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../../&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Salona fell sometime in the early 7th century AD. The descriptions of its fall are rather late, but two events help place it in the first half of the century: A letter from Gregory the Great in 600 A.D. and Pope John IV&amp;rsquo;s rescue of captives in 641 A.D.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Gregory the Great&amp;rsquo;s letter to Maximus, Bishop of Salona, states that he is aware of the danger that the Slavs are posing, and that they are beginning to Enter Italy through Istria. The catalogues of Bishops list two more bishops after Maximus: Frontianus III and Theodore III, but nothing is remembered of how long they held their position or when they died. Farlati believes that Theodore would have been bishop during the destruction of Salona.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximus</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/maximus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 23:45:03 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/maximus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 13 in a series on Daniel Farlati&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../../&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../natalis&#34;&gt;Natalis&lt;/a&gt; died around 593 AD. The archdeacon Honoratus was elected to replace him, but resigned due to the growing political pressure from another bishop named Malchus. John the Deacon writes in &lt;em&gt;Vita Gregorii&lt;/em&gt; that Maximus bribed soldiers in order to ensure he would win the election.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Maximus was the subject of 18 letters written by Gregory the Great over the course of six years. Maximus did not seek consicration from him, instead choosing to go to constantinople. Gregory wrote to the bishops of Dalmatia instructing them not to commune with him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Natalis of Salona</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/natalis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 14:18:23 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/natalis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 12 in a series on Daniel Farlati&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../../&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Natalis became Bishop of Salona in 580 AD. He is remembered for a series of letters that Gregory the Great wrote to him. Gregory admonished him for his wordly life style and for unfairly deposing an two individuals, Honoratus and Florentinus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thomas the Archdeacon summarized the dispute with Honratus in his 11th century work &lt;em&gt;Historiae Salonitanae&lt;/em&gt;. Natalis was a Salonan native who chose feasts and banquets with friends and relatives over service to the church. He also took money from the church treasury to give to friends.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First and Second Councils of Salona</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/sixth-century-councils-of-salona/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2025 16:33:41 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/sixth-century-councils-of-salona/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 11 in a series on Daniel Farlati&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../../&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first and second councils of Salona were said to have taken place in 530 and 533 AD, when Honorius III was Bishop of Salona.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The primary source Farlati refers to is the MS. &lt;em&gt;Bibliothecae Barbarinianae&lt;/em&gt;, a longer manuscript of Thomas the Archdeacon&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Historiae Salonitana&lt;/em&gt;. Johannes Lucius had originally doubted the reliability of the longer version, but Farlati accepts it as authentic. More recently, Vadim Prozorov has reviewed the councils and determined them in harmony with other contemporary councilar laws&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Honorius II,  Januarius, and Stephanus</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/honorius-januarius-and-stephanus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 19:51:41 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/honorius-januarius-and-stephanus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part 10 in a series on Daniel Farlati&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../../&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;honorius-ii&#34;&gt;Honorius II.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Roman Catalog reports a 13 year gap after the death of Glycerius. Honorius II became Bishop of Salona around 493 AD.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Two letters from Pope Gelasius are preserved. Galesius wrote to Honorius because he had heard the Pelagian heresy was spreading in Dalmatia.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following two letters are taken from Minge&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Patrologia Latina&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;first-letter-from-gelasius-to-honorius-ii&#34;&gt;First letter from Gelasius to Honorius II.&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dilectissimo Fratri Honorio Gelasius&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Licet inter varias temporum difficultates continuis occupationibus implicati, vix respirare valeamus; pro sedis tamen apostolicae moderamine totius ovilis dominici curam sine cessatione tractantes, quae beato Petro Salvatoris ipsius nostri voce delegata est: Et tu conversus confirma fratres tuos (Luc. XXII). Et item: Petre, amas me? Pasce oves meas (Joan. XXI). Dissimulare nec possumus nec debemus, quae nostram sollicitudinem forma perstringat, cum beato Paulo apostolo sentientes atque dicentes: Quis infirmatur, et ego non infirmor? Quis scandalizatur, et ego non uror (II Cor. XI)? Ita quippe nos repente tristis, horrenda et vix credibilis confecit opinio, ut mentem nostram confunderet, sauciaret, affligeret. Nuntiatum nobis est enim in regionibus Dalmatiarum, quosdam recidiva Pelagianae pestis zizania seminasse, tantumque illic eorum praevalere blasphemiam, ut simplices quosque mortiferi furoris insinuatione decipiant. Est quidem error ipse nefarius tanto perniciosor ad subripiendum, quanto ad fallendum verisimilitudinis colore versutior: praestante Domino, adest fidei catholicae pura veritas, concordibus universorum Patrum deprompta sententiis, quae et subtile virus funestae pravitatis exponat, et humano generi salvando conferat de Scripturarum confectione medicinam. Nullatenus igitur discretionem rerum nondum abundantia corda conturbet, donec et occultum vulnus appareat, et salvatio singularis eluceat: quoniam quantalibet arte fallaciae spiritus perditionis armetur, sancto gladio Spiritus principalis et detegitur et necatur. Quapropter per dilectionem tuam cunctos ibidem Domini sacerdotes fraterno commonemus affectu; ut qui cum erudiente vos Domino contra novitios pugnetis errores, olim perversitatem toto orbe damnatam nec ipsos recipere debeatis, aut quod temere putatur, esse faciendum; quae non haeresis majoribus nostris convenienter exstincta rursus provocare nos audeat, et palam novis resumptis viribus aperteque confligat. Nunquidnam licet nobis a venerandis Patribus damnata dissolvere, et ab illis excisa nefaria dogmata retractare? Quid est ergo quod magnopere praecavemus, ne cujuslibet haeresis semel dejecta pernicies ad examen denuo venire contendat? Si quae antiquitus a nostris majoribus cognita, discussa, refutata sunt, restauranda nitamur; nonne ipsi nos, quod absit, et quod nunquam catholica patietur Ecclesia, adversariis veritatis universis contra nos resurgendi proponimus exemplum? Ubi est quod scriptum est: Terminos patrum tuorum non transgredieris (Deut. XXXII); et: Interroga patres tuos, et annuntiabunt tibi; et seniores tuos, et dicent tibi? Quid ergo tendimus ultra definita majorum, aut cur nobis non sufficit? Si quid ignorantes discere cupiamus, qualiter ab orthodoxis Patribus et senioribus singula quaeque vel vitanda praecepta sunt, vel aptanda catholicae veritati; cur non his probantur esse decreta? Nunquid aut sapientiores illis sumus, aut poterimus firma stabilitate constare, si ea quae ab illis constituta sunt subruamus? An fortasse nescitis hanc haeresim de qua loquimur, et ab apostolica dudum sede per beatae memoriae Innocentium, ac deinde Zosimum, Bonifacium, Coelestinum, Sixtum, Leonem, continuis et incessabilibus sententiis fuisse prostratam; nec tantum Ecclesiae catholicae legibus, sed principum quoque Romanorum eo tenore damnatam, ut nec usquam terrarum vivendi locum sectatores ejus habere sinerentur? Quae omnia tam gestis Ecclesiae per singulas quasque regiones de eorum pravitate confectis, quam censurae publicae sanctionibus edocentur. Ecce quorumlibet aures catholicas audire doctrinam quaestiones accipere, tractare tendiculas, et blasphemias patienter admittere. O si studerent adversus eos majorum nostrorum libros responsaque cognoscere, illic modis omnibus cerneretur, nihil esse prorsus, quod non et ab istis fuerit ventilatum, et ab illis magnifica veritate contritum. Sicque de cunctis eorum nequitiis refutandis fideles quique redderentur instructi, ut nihil amplius quaereretur. Sed si forsitan ineruditos animos quaedam de eorum sensibus proposita commoverent, ita venerabilium Patrum doctrinis et omnis eorum publicatur insania, et quibus remediis curetur, ostenditur, ut ex his Deo praestante praevisis, cuncta quae de eorum serie texuerunt, et periculosa sectantibus et stulta deprehendentibus esse videantur; ita ut si quis existimet reluctandum, non tamen veterum sententiis contradictor existat, sed humanae saluti, catholicaeque doctrinae palam se a perteque profiteatur inimicum; quo magis attentius pervigil cura pastorum a sacris gregibus luporum debet arcere saevitiam. Num quidquid ovibus sanctis acciderit detrimenti, praesulum (quod absit) damnet incuriam; sicut a regeneratis agminibus nocentium depulsio bestiarum custodum praemiis perpetuum procuravit augmentum? Certe si, ut magis optamus, falsis haec rumoribus sint relata, quantocius desideramus agnoscere, ut qui membrorum Christi vexatione trepidamus, multo magis de eorum stabilitate laetemur. Data V kalendas Augusti, a Fausto [ al. Albino] V. C. consule (anno Christi 493).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glycerius</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/glycerius/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 16:54:06 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/glycerius/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part nine in a series on Daniel Farlatis &lt;a href=&#34;../../&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before becoming Bishop of Salona, Glycerius was emperor of the Western Roman Empire. In June 474, a little over a year in to his reign, Julius Nepos deposed him and consecrated him as bishop of Salona. This was not the first time an Emperor had been deposed and made bishop. 30 years prior, Avitus was defeated in battle by Ricimer and was made bishop of Piacenza. The Deposition of Glycerius was documented by 6th century writers Marcellinus Comes, Jordanes, and Evagrius Scholasticus. Little is known about his short reign. He receives a favorable mention by Ennodius in his work on the life of Epiphanius of Pavia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XML in Go</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/xml-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 15:30:37 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/xml-in-go/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;decoding&#34;&gt;Decoding&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this section we&amp;rsquo;ll examine the rules of the xml decoder and provide examples for each.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;1-if-the-struct-has-a-field-type-byte-or-string-with-tag-innerxml-unmarshal-accumulates-the-raw-xml-nested-inside-in-that-field-the-rest-of-the-rules-still-apply&#34;&gt;1. If the struct has a field type []byte or string with tag &amp;ldquo;,innerxml&amp;rdquo;, Unmarshal accumulates the raw XML nested inside in that field. The rest of the rules still apply.&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Go&#34; data-lang=&#34;Go&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;`&amp;lt;address&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;        &amp;lt;street&amp;gt;123 Main St&amp;lt;/street&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;    &amp;lt;/address&amp;gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Address&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; {&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Contents&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;`xml:&amp;#34;,innerxml&amp;#34;`&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Volume&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;xml&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Unmarshal&lt;/span&gt;([]byte(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;), &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt; {&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Fatal&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;fmt&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Println&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Contents&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;//  &amp;lt;street&amp;gt;123 Main St&amp;lt;/street&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h5 id=&#34;2-if-the-struct-has-a-field-named-xmlname-of-type-name-unmarshal-records-the-element-name-in-that-field&#34;&gt;2. If the struct has a field named XMLName of type Name, Unmarshal records the element name in that field.&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Go&#34; data-lang=&#34;Go&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;`&amp;lt;address&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;        &amp;lt;street&amp;gt;123 Main St&amp;lt;/street&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;    &amp;lt;/address&amp;gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Address&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; {&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;XMLName&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;xml&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Name&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Address&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;xml&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Unmarshal&lt;/span&gt;([]byte(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;), &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt; {&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Fatal&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;fmt&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Printf&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;%+v&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;XMLName&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Local&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;// address&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h5 id=&#34;3-if-the-xmlname-field-has-an-associated-tag-of-the-form-name-or-namespace-url-name-the-xml-element-must-have-the-given-name-and-optionally-name-space-or-else-unmarshal-returns-an-error&#34;&gt;3. If the XMLName field has an associated tag of the form &amp;ldquo;name&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;namespace-URL name&amp;rdquo;, the XML element must have the given name (and, optionally, name space) or else Unmarshal returns an error.&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Go&#34; data-lang=&#34;Go&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;`&amp;lt;address&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;        &amp;lt;street&amp;gt;123 Main St&amp;lt;/street&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;    &amp;lt;/address&amp;gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Address&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; {&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;XMLName&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;xml&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;`xml:&amp;#34;city&amp;#34;`&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Address&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;xml&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Unmarshal&lt;/span&gt;([]byte(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;), &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt; {&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Fatal&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;//expected element type &amp;lt;city&amp;gt; but have &amp;lt;address&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;}&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h5 id=&#34;4-if-the-xml-element-has-an-attribute-whose-name-matches-a-struct-field-name-with-an-associated-tag-containing-attr-or-the-explicit-name-in-a-struct-field-tag-of-the-form-nameattr-unmarshal-records-the-attribute-value-in-that-field&#34;&gt;4. If the XML element has an attribute whose name matches a struct field name with an associated tag containing &amp;ldquo;,attr&amp;rdquo; or the explicit name in a struct field tag of the form &amp;ldquo;name,attr&amp;rdquo;, Unmarshal records the attribute value in that field.&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Go&#34; data-lang=&#34;Go&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;`&amp;lt;address id=&amp;#34;999&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;        &amp;lt;street&amp;gt;123 Main St&amp;lt;/street&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;    &amp;lt;/address&amp;gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Address&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; {&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Id&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;`xml:&amp;#34;id,attr&amp;#34;`&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Address&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;xml&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Unmarshal&lt;/span&gt;([]byte(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;), &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt; {&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Fatal&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;fmt&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Println&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Id&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;//999&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h5 id=&#34;5-if-the-xml-element-has-an-attribute-not-handled-by-the-previous-rule-and-the-struct-has-a-field-with-an-associated-tag-containing-anyattr-unmarshal-records-the-attribute-value-in-the-first-such-field&#34;&gt;5. If the XML element has an attribute not handled by the previous rule and the struct has a field with an associated tag containing &amp;ldquo;,any,attr&amp;rdquo;, Unmarshal records the attribute value in the first such field.&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Go&#34; data-lang=&#34;Go&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;`&amp;lt;address id=&amp;#34;999&amp;#34; span=&amp;#34;888&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;        &amp;lt;street&amp;gt;123 Main St&amp;lt;/street&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;    &amp;lt;/address&amp;gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Address&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; {&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Id&lt;/span&gt;        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;`xml:&amp;#34;id,attr&amp;#34;`&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;OtherAttr&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;`xml:&amp;#34;,any,attr&amp;#34;`&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Address&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;xml&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Unmarshal&lt;/span&gt;([]byte(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;), &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt; {&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Fatal&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;fmt&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Printf&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;%+v&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;// {Id:999, OtherAttr:888}&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h5 id=&#34;6-if-the-xml-element-contains-character-data-that-data-is-accumulated-in-the-first-struct-field-that-has-tag-chardata-the-struct-field-may-have-type-byte-or-string-if-there-is-no-such-field-the-character-data-is-discarded&#34;&gt;6. If the XML element contains character data, that data is accumulated in the first struct field that has tag &amp;ldquo;,chardata&amp;rdquo;. The struct field may have type []byte or string. If there is no such field, the character data is discarded.&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Go&#34; data-lang=&#34;Go&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;`&amp;lt;address&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;        &amp;lt;street&amp;gt;123 Main St&amp;lt;/street&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;    &amp;lt;/address&amp;gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Address&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; {&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Street&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; {&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Text&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;`xml:&amp;#34;,chardata&amp;#34;`&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    } &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;`xml:&amp;#34;street&amp;#34;`&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Address&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;xml&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Unmarshal&lt;/span&gt;([]byte(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;), &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt; {&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Fatal&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;fmt&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Println&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Street&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Text&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h5 id=&#34;7-if-the-xml-element-contains-comments-they-are-accumulated-in-the-first-struct-field-that-has-tag-comment-the-struct-field-may-have-type-byte-or-string-if-there-is-no-such-field-the-comments-are-discarded&#34;&gt;7. If the XML element contains comments, they are accumulated in the first struct field that has tag &amp;ldquo;,comment&amp;rdquo;. The struct field may have type []byte or string. If there is no such field, the comments are discarded.&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Go&#34; data-lang=&#34;Go&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;`&amp;lt;address&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;        &amp;lt;!-- an xml comment --&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;        &amp;lt;street&amp;gt;123 Main St&amp;lt;/street&amp;gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;    &amp;lt;/address&amp;gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Address&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;struct&lt;/span&gt; {&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;`xml:&amp;#34;,comment&amp;#34;`&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Address&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;:=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;xml&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Unmarshal&lt;/span&gt;([]byte(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;x&lt;/span&gt;), &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;!=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;nil&lt;/span&gt; {&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Fatal&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;err&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;fmt&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Println&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;addr&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;Comment&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#75715e&#34;&gt;// an xml comment&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h5 id=&#34;8-if-the-xml-element-contains-a-sub-element-whose-name-matches-the-prefix-of-a-tag-formatted-as-a-or-abc-unmarshal-will-descend-into-the-xml-structure-looking-for-elements-with-the-given-names-and-will-map-the-innermost-elements-to-that-struct-field-a-tag-starting-with--is-equivalent-to-one-starting-with-the-field-name-followed-by-&#34;&gt;8. If the XML element contains a sub-element whose name matches the prefix of a tag formatted as &amp;ldquo;a&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;a&amp;gt;b&amp;gt;c&amp;rdquo;, unmarshal will descend into the XML structure looking for elements with the given names, and will map the innermost elements to that struct field. A tag starting with &amp;ldquo;&amp;gt;&amp;rdquo; is equivalent to one starting with the field name followed by &amp;ldquo;&amp;gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This one is worth dividing in to several examples: The most basic is when a sub-element name that matches a tag.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hesychius of Solana</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/hesychius/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 22:36:42 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume2/hesychius/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part eight in a series on Daniel Farlati&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../../&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hesychius became bishop of Salona around 405 AD. He is most remembered for the letters he sent and received from his contemporaries: John Chrysostom, Augustine of Hippo, and Pope Zosimus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#letter-from-john-chrysostom&#34;&gt;Letter from John chrysostom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#correspondence-with-pope-zosimus&#34;&gt;Letter from Pope Zoesimus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#correspondence-with-augustine&#34;&gt;Letter to Augustine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;#life-of-clement&#34;&gt;Life of Clement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;letter-from-john-chrysostom&#34;&gt;Letter from John Chrysostom&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A short letter from John Chrysostom sent after his exile. Epistle 183.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Esti magno itineris intervallo a reverentia tua disjungimur, et ad extremos usque orbis terrarum fines relegati sumus; tamen levi charitatis penna utentes, quae faciles reddit huiusmodi peregrinationes, et propinqui fumus tibi, et tecum versamur, ac debitam per litteras salutationem persolvimus; teque hortamur, ut ad juvandas orientis ecclesias conveniens studium adhibeas. Scis enim, quanta fit parata merces ei, qui divexatis ecclesiis manum porrexerit, et tantam procellam in tranquillitatem converterit, ac bellum adeo grave restinxerit. Atque ad haec vos hortamur, non quasi admonitione nostra indigtatis; siquidem antequam hostras litteras accepissetis, quae vestri muneris erant, ipsi praestitistis; sed quia nondum sublata sunt mala, sed adhuc vigent, et urgent; oramus vos, ut ne animo concidatis, neque malis cedatis, sed quamdiu manent ulcera, quibus cclesiae corpus affligitur, vestra medicamenta adhibeatis. Quanto enim pluribus cum laboribus res geruntur, tanto vobis amplior etimam merces constituetur.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Illyricum Sacrum Volume 1: Table of Contents</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume1/table-of-contents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 17:02:36 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume1/table-of-contents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having written about the parts I found interesting in Volume 1 of &lt;a href=&#34;../../&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;, I provide here a translation of the table of contents, along with my notes, for anyone who may be interested in further exploring this volume.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;dedication-and-preface&#34;&gt;Dedication and Preface&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dedication to Pope Benedict XIV.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Preface by Pacifico Bizza.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;notes-on-the-dedication-and-preface&#34;&gt;notes on the dedication and preface:&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Benedict XIV: Pope from 1740-1758.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pacifico Bizza: Archbishop of Split from 1746-1756.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;prolegomenon-part-1&#34;&gt;Prolegomenon Part 1.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;of-illyrica&#34;&gt;Of Illyrica&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-on-the-pelasgians-founders-of-the-illyrian-nation-1&#34;&gt;1. On the Pelasgians, founders of the Illyrian nation 1&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the origin of the name and race of the Illyrians.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The original and proper boundaries of Illyricum.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The first spread of Illyricum. The destruction of the kingdom of Hyllus, his Successors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;notes-on-the-illyrians&#34;&gt;Notes on the Illyrians.&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Early Illyrian references:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anastasius the Fuller</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume1/anastasius-the-fuller/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 11:58:54 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume1/anastasius-the-fuller/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part seven in a series on Daniel Farlati&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../../&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;: Volume 1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Anastasius the Fuller is the last saint discussed in Volume 1. He is still remembered in Split with an altar in the Cathedral of saint Domnius. Farlati publishes 3 versions of his &lt;em&gt;acts&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;from a manuscript found in the monastery of Mont-Saint-Michel, France.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;from a manuscript from the library of Apostolo Zeno.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;from a slavonic manuscript, otherwise unknown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The acts are short. Anastasius, a fuller by trade who lived in Aquila, feels called to travel to Salona during the diocletian persecution. Unashamed of his Christian faith, he paints a cross in to the door of his residence. The city officials seeing this have Anastasius flogged, tie a stone around his neck and throw him in to the sea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donatus</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume1/donatus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 20:18:30 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume1/donatus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is Part six in a series on Daniel Farlati&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../../&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;: Volume 1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;acts&lt;/em&gt; of Donatus are found in a manuscript in the Biblioteca Medicea Laurenziana collection&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. A latin translation was made by Daniel Cardonus and published in the &lt;em&gt;Acta Sanctorum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. No other mentions of this Donatus are found, and the historical accuracy of events is highly questionable. The manuscript seems to have been composed in Dalmatia, it&amp;rsquo;s prologue making direct mention of Salona. Farlati includes them in Illyricum Sacrum as they mention Donatus traveling to Salona and living on the nearby mountain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>George of Salona</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume1/george-of-salona/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 20:26:36 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume1/george-of-salona/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part five in a series on Daniel Farleti&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../../&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;: Volume 1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Farlati lists George (lt. Georgius) as 17th on the list of bishops of Salona. Like most of the early bishops of Salona, there is little memory of him. Farlati Attributes these forgotten bishops to the sacking of Salona by the slavs in the 7th century. He believes that George was forgotten in Salona but remembered elsewhere. Over time, his acts became intermixed with the megalomartyr George. Conveniently, he gives a late 3rd century date for George of Salona so he can extract what he believes where originally &lt;em&gt;acts&lt;/em&gt; of the Solanan George from the &lt;em&gt;acts&lt;/em&gt; of the megalomartyr.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agapitus and Anastasius</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume1/agapitus-and-anastasius/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 22:50:50 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume1/agapitus-and-anastasius/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part four in a series on Daniel Farleti&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../../&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;: Volume 1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Agapitus, also called Amabilis, is 15th on the list of Solanan bishops. He is remembered together with Anastasius, who was said to have converted to Christianity&#xA;after witnessing Agapitus face persecution. Their lives are dated to the reign of emperor Aurelian in the late third century.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As recorded in the Martyrology of Ado:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In civitate Salona natalis Anastasii Martyris, qui cum videret B. Agapitum inter tormenta fortiter Christum consitentem, exclamavit, Magnus est Deus Christianorum, et non est alius preter eum.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venantius of Salona</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume1/venantius/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 18:48:30 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume1/venantius/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part three in a series on Daniel Farleti&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../../&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;: Volume 1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Venantius appears sixth on the list of bishops of Salona. Between Domnius and Venantius are four bishops of which little is known about. The first two are Cajunus&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and Symphoranius, listed as successors to Domnius In the version of the &lt;em&gt;acts&lt;/em&gt; of Domnius found in the collection of Šimun Kožičić Benja. This version of the &lt;em&gt;acts&lt;/em&gt; state Clement of Rome personally traveled to Salona and appointed them. They were followed by Hesychius I&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and Hesychius II, and Venantius.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saint Domnius: The First Bishop of Salona</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume1/domnius-bishop-of-salona/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 20:30:06 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume1/domnius-bishop-of-salona/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part two in a series on Daniel Farleti&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;../../&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;: Volume 1.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Domnius is traditionally held to be the first bishop of Salona, near modern day Solin, Croatia. Farlati provides an early reference to Domnius found in the Hieronymiaus Martyrology&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In Salona Dalmatia a Domionis episcopi &amp;amp; militam Dalmati&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He provides a second, more controversial reference purporting to be from Hesychius, a 5th century Bishop of Salona, in a work titled &lt;em&gt;Vita S. Clementis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Illyricum Sacrum</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 19:42:30 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/em&gt; is the result of a lifelong effort by the Italian priest Filippo Riceputi to document as many sources on the history of the church in the Balkan region and former Roman province of Illyricum. It spans 8 volumes which were compiled and published after his death by Daniele Farlati.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;volume-1&#34;&gt;Volume 1&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Volume 1 focuses on the historical region of Illyricum. The history of the church at Salona, A former Dalmatian city located near present day Solin, Croatia, is discussed from the 1st to 4th century BC. I provide a translation of the table of contents, along with some posts on the various saints discussed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Illyricum Sacrum Volume 1: introduction</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume1/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 19:42:30 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/illyricum-sacrum/volume1/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The introduction(&lt;em&gt;Prolegomenon&lt;/em&gt;) to Volume 1 of &lt;a href=&#34;../../../illyricum-sacrum&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt; consists of three parts: A history of the region of Illyricum, a history of the region of Dalmatia, and a history of the origins of the Church in these regions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Farlati pours through ancient Greek and Roman sources for every reference to Illyria and Dalmatia he can find. Pomponius Mela, Strabo, Polybius, Appian of Alexandria, and Livy are all quoted generously. After exhausting the ancient writers, he turns to more recent publications. Johannes Lucius’ 17th century work on the history of Dalmatia, &lt;em&gt;De Regno Dalmatiae et Croatiae&lt;/em&gt;, and Johann Ludwig Schönleben(Ludovicus Schonlebius) who wrote &lt;em&gt;Carniola antiqua et nova&lt;/em&gt;, a history of the region today known as Slovenia. One of the more obscure references cited is Francesco Maria Mezzabarba (&lt;em&gt;mediobarbi&lt;/em&gt;), who wrote a 17th century work &lt;em&gt;Imperatorum Romanorum Numismata&lt;/em&gt;, cataloguing Roman Coins, some of which included inscriptions of Illyria on them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latin</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/latin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 19:42:30 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/latin/latin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This page explores latin texts, primarily those with no English translation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1600s&#34;&gt;1600s&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../illyricum-sacrum&#34;&gt;Illyricum Sacrum&lt;/a&gt;: an 8 volume work on the history of church in former Roman province of Illyricum.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Imperatorum Romanorum Numismata&lt;/em&gt;, Francesco Maria Mezzabarba&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Carniola antiqua et nova&lt;/em&gt;, Ludwig Schönleben&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;De Regno Dalmatiae et Croatiae&lt;/em&gt;, Johannes Lucius&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1200s&#34;&gt;1200s&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Historia Salonitana&lt;/em&gt;, Thomas the Archdeacon&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bitwise Addition</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/bitwise-addition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 20:32:41 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/bitwise-addition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a function that can add two numbers using bitwise operators.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-Go&#34; data-lang=&#34;Go&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;func&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;bitwise_add&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; {&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; {&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;        &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    }&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;bitwise_add&lt;/span&gt;(&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;^&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;, (&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;b&lt;/span&gt;) &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;)&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;}&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why does this work? It&amp;rsquo;s helpful to look at this function not as performing &amp;ldquo;addition&amp;rdquo;, but in using the bitwise operators to &lt;em&gt;rewrite&lt;/em&gt; a mathematical expression.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s show this concretely with two numbers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let a = 5 as the expression $2^2 + 2^0$&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Let b = 7 as the expression $2^2 + 2^1 + 2^0$&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Let the sum of 5 and 7 be represented the expression&#xA;$2^2 + 2^2 + 2^1 + 2^0 + 2^0$&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing a Mock Library in Go</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/writing-a-mock-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 13:34:16 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/writing-a-mock-library/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post will walk through the core components that make the mock package from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stretchr/testify&#34;&gt;Testify&lt;/a&gt; work. It consists of 3 parts:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;a &lt;code&gt;mock&lt;/code&gt; object that keeps track of expected calls&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;a &lt;code&gt;call&lt;/code&gt; object that keeps track of expected arguments and return values&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;an algorithm to fetch the return values when called.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Mock&lt;/code&gt; is a struct with an Array of &lt;code&gt;Calls&lt;/code&gt; and a mutual exclusion lock to ensure only one goroutine accesses the resource at a time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Practical Use Case for Higher Order Functions</title>
      <link>https://tscales.github.io/blog/higher-order-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 11:02:32 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://tscales.github.io/blog/higher-order-functions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever encountered this scenario before?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lets say you have a class &lt;code&gt;User&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-scala&#34; data-lang=&#34;scala&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;case&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#a6e22e&#34;&gt;User&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;firstName&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; lastName&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; address&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;String&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re using this class in production to store information retrieved from an endpoint. Now imagine you are given a new task where you need to fetch a User from a new endpoint. However, This endpoint &lt;em&gt;does not contain the address field&lt;/em&gt;, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to get that field from a second new endpoint. What do you do?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
